<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About me on Daniel Severo</title>
    <link>https://dsevero.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About me on Daniel Severo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 14:33:30 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dsevero.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Handling Time-series in Pandas and Numpy.</title>
      <link>https://dsevero.com/posts/pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 14:33:30 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsevero.com/posts/pandas/</guid>
      <description>Here we will show you how to properly use the Python Data Analysis Library (pandas) and numpy. The agenda is:
How to load data from csv files The basic pandas objects: DataFrames and Series Handling Time-Series data Resampling (optional) From pandas to numpy Simple Linear Regression Consider leaving a Star if this helps you.
The following ipython magic (this is literally the name) will enable plots made by matplotlib to be rendered inside this notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad hoc Big Data Analysis with Dask</title>
      <link>https://dsevero.com/posts/dask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsevero.com/posts/dask/</guid>
      <description>How can we keep the simplicity and power of pandas, while extending it to be out-of-core and parallel?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning From Data, Problem 1.7</title>
      <link>https://dsevero.com/posts/lfd-p17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsevero.com/posts/lfd-p17/</guid>
      <description>This post is a solution to the problem taken from Abu-Mostafa, Yaser S., Malik Magdon-Ismail, and Hsuan-Tien Lin. Learning from data. Vol. 4. New York, NY, USA:: AMLBook, 2012..
Quoted text refers to the original problem statement, verbatim.
For more solutions, see dsevero.com/blog.
Consider leaving a Star if this helps you.
A sample of heads and tails is created by tossing a coin a number of times independently. Assume we have a number of coins that generate different samples independently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://dsevero.com/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsevero.com/reading/</guid>
      <description>Things I think are worth reading. Consider leaving a Star if this helps you.
Statistical Learning Theory # Shalev-Shwartz, Shai, and Shai Ben-David. Understanding machine learning: From theory to algorithms. Cambridge university press, 2014. [book] [lectures] Abu-Mostafa, Yaser S., Malik Magdon-Ismail, and Hsuan-Tien Lin. Learning from data. Vol. 4. New York, NY, USA:: AMLBook, 2012. [book] ISIT 2018 - S. Kannan, H. Kim &amp;amp; S. Oh - Deep learning and information theory An Emerging Interface [video] [slides] Ashish Khisti.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
